

### Sebastiano Ferraris

Geospatial Data Scientist, PhD

### **Contacts**

**♀** London

sebastiano.ferraris@gmail.com

geospatial.netlify.app

github.com/SebastianoF

in linkedin.com/in/ibis-redibis/

**G** Google Scholar

Research Gate

## **Skills**

Software development	9+ years
Data science	9+ years
Algorithms	9+ years
Artificial intelligence	4+ years
Geospatial Data Science	3+ years
Medical image analysis	4 years
Discrete Events Simulation	1 year
Dynamic pricing	1 year

## **Summary**

Problem solving addict, researcher and data scientist with publications on international journals. Worked and solved problems in a range of domains, such as Automtive Industry, Medical Image Analysis, Banking, Dynamic Pricing and Geotemporal Data Science.

Driven towards creating algorithms, mathematical models, data processing pipelines, and analysing bottlenecks and code performances, I am specialised in creating prototypes and algorithms to solve relevant and important problems, communicate results to a diverse audience, from neophytes to stakeholders, testing the prototypes and handing them over to the dev team, for deployment and scalability aimed at productionisation.

### **Experience**

#### Data scientist | General System

June 2020 - today

Geospatial data Science Services: Startup in stealth mode until April 2022

- Developing prototypes to automate spatiotemporal data analysis at scale with clustering methods, dashboards and KeplerGl visualisation.
- Collaborating with clients and domain experts to quickly and iteratively integrate feedback into prototypes.
- Prototypes handover to production and DevSecOps teams.
- Developing and open sourcing python libraries to provide users tooling and examples for the Data Flow Index.
- Contributing to the company blog aimed at building a community around the hot topics of spatiotemporal data science.

#### Algorithm Engineer | Pace

Sept 2019 - June 2020

Dynamic pricing for the hospitality industry

- Simulation and Validation team, aimed at validate and test the python-based ETL pipelines and the core algorithms.
- Production code maintenance and new features integration.

#### **Back End Developer | Thought Machine**

Oct 2018 - June 2019

- Cloud native core banking
- State-of-the-art infrastructure technologies to deploy microservices in a cloud-agnostic environment: Python, Go, Docker, Kubernetes, and derived customisations.
- Maintenance and improvement of the Thought Machine's CI/CD and release pipelines.

### $\mathsf{MRes} + \mathsf{PhD} \; \mathsf{in} \; \mathsf{Medical} \; \mathsf{Image} \; \mathsf{analysis} \; | \; \textcolor{red}{\mathsf{UCL}}$

Sept 2014 - Sept 2018

Research Student

- Pre-clinical trial on pre-term birth steroids administration in a multidisciplinary international research team.
- Published 7 peer reviewed papers also on Neuroimage and Nature Scientific Report about diffeomorphic image registration and Machine Learning for automated MRI segmentation.
- Reproducible research advocate: open sourced 12 Python libraries (Sec 7.2.2 of my PhD Thesis), and one micro MRI dataset.

### **Education**

2015 - 2018

# PhD, Centre for Doctoral Training (EPSRC), Medical Imaging

University College London

MRI • Pre-clinical studies • Numerical methods for Image registration • 8 Papers published • 12 repositories open sourced

2014 - 2015

### Master of Research (MRes), Medical Imaging

University College London

Numerical methods for image registration • Digital Image Processing

Optics in Medicine

2010 - 2013

#### Master of Science (MSci), Mathematics

Universita degli studi di Torino

Geometry • Error correcting code theory • Computational modelling.

2006 - 2010

# Bachelor's of Science (BSc), Mathematics

Universita degli studi di Torino

# Vounteering

- Maths Tutor, Action Tutoring
- Scanner and Marshall, Parkrun

#### Industrial Simulation Modeller | SimTec

Automotive industry, discrete events simulation

 Material flow simulation models to estimate efficiency, remove bottlenecks, dimension buffers and support plant layout design for a range of clients in Italy and Germany.

- In house shortest paths algorithms development for the internal and external logistics of assembly parts, from plant's gate to assembly line.
- Presented at the first annual Tecnomatix Plant Simulation User Conference in Stuttgart.

#### Developer | TcWeb

June 2011 - Oct 2011

March 2013 - June 2014

Web development and technology consulting

- Term contracts as Junior Developer in Java, Java J2EE, Struts 2, Uml.
- Algorithms developer: prototyped and implemented a generalised Hungarian Algorithm to parse newspapers' pages.

### Selected Publications

- Ferraris S, van der Merwe J, Van Der Veeken L, Prados F, Iglesias JE, Melbourne A, Lorenzi M, Modat M, Gsell W, Deprest J, Vercauteren T. "A magnetic resonance multi-atlas for the neonatal rabbit brain". Neuroimage. *Neuroimage* 2018 Oct doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2018.06.029.
- van der Merwe J, van der Veeken L, Ferraris S, Gsell W, Himmelreich U, Toelen J, Ourselin S, Melbourne A, Vercauteren T, Deprest J. "Early neuropathological and neurobehavioral consequences of preterm birth in a rabbit model". In: Nature scientific reports, May 2019.
- Ferraris S, Lorenzi M, Daga P, Modat M, Vercauteren T. "Accurate small deformation exponential approximant to integrate large velocity fields: Application to image registration". In: Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, Lipsum, June 12-17, 2020.
- Ferraris S, Shakir ID, Van Der Merwe J, Gsell W, Deprest J, Vercauteren T
  "Bruker2nifti: Magnetic resonance images converter from bruker ParaVision to
  NIfTI format". In: Journal of Open Source Software, 2017.
- Ferraris S "Image computing tools for the investigation of the neurological effects of preterm birth and corticosteroid administration" PhD thesis, University College London, 2019.

Please see my Google Scholar Profile for the complete list of publications.

30th .	January	2024
--------	---------	------

Sebastiano Ferraris